<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Suvi Heikkuri</title><link>https://suvihe.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Suvi Heikkuri</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://suvihe.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>About</title><link>https://suvihe.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://suvihe.github.io/about/</guid><description>I am a Ph.D. student in the Unit of Economic History at the University of Gothenburg. My dissertation project titled &amp;ldquo;Technological change, skills, and occupational structure in Sweden, 1870 - 1950&amp;rdquo; looks into how technological change has influenced employment and skills during industrialization in Sweden. My supervisor is Svante Prado.
Education Ph.D., Economic History (expected 2024) School of Business, Economics, and Law
University of Gothenburg
Gothenburg, Sweden
M.Sc., Innovation and Spatial Dynamics (2019) School of Economics and Management</description></item><item><title>Occupational structure and skill composition of the Swedish labor markets, 1870–2010</title><link>https://suvihe.github.io/projects/occupational_structure_sweden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://suvihe.github.io/projects/occupational_structure_sweden/</guid><description>Summary This project examines the occupational structure and skill composition in Sweden during its rapid industrialization phase from 1870s onward. More specifically, it aims to find evidence of skill-biased or task-biased technological change, and whether the changes in skill composition resulted in changes in income inequality among workers. Furthermore, the project aims to account for differential regional outcomes, migration, and the supply of skilled workers during the period under study.</description></item><item><title>The skill content of technological change in Sweden, 1870–1920</title><link>https://suvihe.github.io/projects/skill_change_sweden/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://suvihe.github.io/projects/skill_change_sweden/</guid><description>Summary Technological change is an important source for long-term economic growth, but it may also affect the labor markets by creating and eliminating jobs. While new technologies have not caused massive unemployment, there has been a change in the type of jobs over time, which may affect inequality. Contemporary studies have shown that technological change has caused labor polarization through decreasing demand for middling skills while increasing demand for skills at both ends of the skill distribution.</description></item></channel></rss>